[{"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c633", "question": "What are the twin stars in the constellation of Gemini called?", "answer": "Pollux and Castor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe12f17e39efa6330e0fed6", "question": "Where is Great Sand Dunes National Park?", "answer": "Colorado", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cf5", "question": "In what movies is the Okinawan sword-maker Hattori Hanzo a character?", "answer": "Kill Bill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d04", "question": "Whose sidekick was named Paul Shaffer?", "answer": "David Letterman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4bba49076251badbeac7", "question": "How many rooms are there in Buckingham Palace (total number)?", "answer": "775 -- It includes 19 State rooms, 92 offices, 52 Royal and guest bedrooms, 188 bedrooms for staff and 78 bathrooms.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febbc557e83c707845b214b", "question": "Which NFL player later went on to become a US Supreme Court Judge?", "answer": "Byron White who was a runner-up to the Heisman Trophy in 1937, served as an Associate Supreme Court Justice from 1962 to 1993.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c008", "question": "In 1946, Yvon Petra was the last Wimbledon champion to do what?", "answer": "Wear trousers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c85a", "question": "What disease grounded astronaut Ken Mattingly from Apollo 13?", "answer": "The measles", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6014c7aafbde8045e48466c6", "question": "What is the only marsupial found in the U.S. and Canada?", "answer": "Opossum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c588", "question": "What is an adult male polar bear referred to as?", "answer": "A boar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133892a", "question": "In Larry Niven's novel \"Ringworld\", what is the drug that extends human life to near immortality?", "answer": "Boosterspice", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a143", "question": "Who plays Auntie Wainwright in the TV show \"Last Of The Summer Wine\"?", "answer": "Jean Alexander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab42", "question": "What is the capital of Austria?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf08", "question": "What crime has a person committed if they have been convicted of Regicide?", "answer": "They have killed the King", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c888", "question": "What scoop out cirques, coombs, and corries?", "answer": "Glaciers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd74", "question": "What branch of philosophy deals with the end of the world?", "answer": "Eschatology", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e8a88fa404ad935a7e1a63e", "question": "Which composer began to lose his hearing at age 26?", "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a162cc3f01ec323f8491732", "question": "Arnold Schwarzenegger played Douglas Quaid in which 1990 film?", "answer": "Total Recall", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f9", "question": "In which South American country is the Atacama desert?", "answer": "Chile", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133991c", "question": "Who occupied the center square on the game show \u201cThe Hollywood Squares\u201d from 1998\u00ad to 2002?", "answer": "Whoopi Goldberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c35", "question": "The Grammy Awards are depicted by what gold plated musical object?", "answer": "The gramophone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a26", "question": "Whose \"Small House\" is the subject of the play acted out during \"The King and I\"?", "answer": "Uncle Thomas'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d0", "question": "What is a turkey stuffed with a duck stuffed with a chicken called?", "answer": "Turducken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5b1743f2bb2d29f81593b6f7", "question": "How is Barbara Millicent Roberts better known as?", "answer": "Barbie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af5a", "question": "Which British Prime Minister was assassinated in 1812?", "answer": "Spencer Percival", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dbf", "question": "Whose garden is infiltrated by Peter Rabbit?", "answer": "Mr. McGregor's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339461", "question": "Who played Hank Grotowski in the movie \"Monster's Ball\"?", "answer": "Billy Bob Thornton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa2c", "question": "Which is the largest lake by area in the British Isles?", "answer": "Lough Neagh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9dc", "question": "What is a group of whales commonly called?", "answer": "Pod", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfcc", "question": "What colour is Creme de menthe?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594d06b51a1c922dd1ac64af", "question": "What's the official state sport of Alaska?", "answer": "Dog mushing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c152", "question": "What is a group of locusts called?", "answer": "Plague", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600397f857a0e35c43f83899", "question": "What term did the artist Kurt Schwitters invent to describe his works made from scavenged fragments and objects?", "answer": "Father of installation art and a pioneer in fusing collage and abstraction, invented the term\u00a0Merz from the German word\u00a0Kommerz.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bba7", "question": "Which one of tennis' Grand Slam tournaments is held in January?", "answer": "Australian Open", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91d", "question": "Which part of the body does the adjective \"renal\" refer to?", "answer": "Kidney", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa8bc6ce05a3942286ed6", "question": "Who played the part of Max Cady in the 1962 thriller \"Cape Fear\"?", "answer": "Robert Mitchum", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca4d", "question": "An Apgar score is given to what?", "answer": "Health of newborns", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b674", "question": "What airport did the first commercial Boeing 747 flight from JFK land at?", "answer": "London, Heathrow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb5c795dad637d903c881e", "question": "\"Ital\" is the word used to describe the cuisine of which group of people?", "answer": "Rastafarians", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab1b36b4fda37788a9a1dc2", "question": "What comes in varieties freestone and clingstone?", "answer": "Peaches", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d3", "question": "On what holiday did Harry Houdini die in 1926?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58c8a5ba90aac110e4167075", "question": "What does a Tegestologist collect?", "answer": "Beer coasters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca71", "question": "What term is applied to animals or plants that are not nocturnal?", "answer": "Diurnal", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbc1", "question": "For what college did Dan Marino play football?", "answer": "University of Pittsburgh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339239", "question": "Who performed \"Bitter Sweet Symphony\" with Coldplay at the Live 8 concert?", "answer": "Richard Ashcroft", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5952427f736d4be723796b64", "question": "How old was Ruby Bridges on her first day at her new school in Louisiana?", "answer": "6 years old", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e10", "question": "Philosopher Hannah Arendt's most famous book is named for what man \"in Jerusalem\"?", "answer": "Adolf Eichmann", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e5", "question": "Barn, Burrowing, and Great Horned are species of what bird?", "answer": "Owl", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4e8", "question": "In which European city can you find the \"Mouth of Truth\"?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b2b", "question": "In the Marvel Comics world, who has an assistant named Pepper Potts?", "answer": "Tony Stark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "60078c700eee65b76b9f2673", "question": "What is the Statue of Liberty holding in her left hand?", "answer": "She holds a tablet inscribed with the date of the U.S. Declaration of Independence \u2014 July 4, 1776. It is nearly 24 ft. long.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e0", "question": "Who wrote the first three books of the \"Millennium\" novel series?", "answer": "Stieg Larsson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339806", "question": "By what name is the musician, Charles Hardin, better known as?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0c", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal whose mascot was Sugar Bear?", "answer": "Super Sugar Crisp", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fcc1c5bc97eb73f6a51a273", "question": "What is the longest mountain range on land?", "answer": "The Andes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b0", "question": "What nation was led by Sargon the Great?", "answer": "Akkad", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8f8", "question": "How long is a round in boxing?", "answer": "3 minutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b950", "question": "What holiday do Americans celebrate on the third Monday in January?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr. Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a5", "question": "What bones did James Dean break in the movie \"Rebel Without A Cause\"?", "answer": "His knuckles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a0", "question": "What is the name of Dr. Seuss's egg-hatching elephant?", "answer": "Horton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133900e", "question": "What was Tom Clancy's blockbuster first novel, published in 1984?", "answer": "The Hunt for Red October", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59412664bab1e6f9796f1b58", "question": "How long does a day last on Uranus?", "answer": "17 hours", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133909a", "question": "In Greek mythology, who were Hera's parents?", "answer": "Cronus and Rhea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8d4", "question": "What does the abbreviation VH1 stand for in the TV station by the same name?", "answer": "Video Hits 1", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac63", "question": "Which US naval base did Japan attack in 1941 to declare war on the Allies?", "answer": "Pearl Harbor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3bc", "question": "What is the common name for butterfly larvae?", "answer": "Caterpillars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a649", "question": "Lincoln is the capital of which state?", "answer": "Nebraska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bbd535000d154d7af00b8dc", "question": "Which band recorded and released the song\"Cotton Eye Joe\"?", "answer": "Rednex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b669", "question": "What automaker produced a luxury model named \"Imperial\" in 1926?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfd7", "question": "What is the NATO phonetic alphabet word for \"R\"?", "answer": "Romeo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b438", "question": "Which historical figure passed away on April 18, 1955?", "answer": "Albert Einstein", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ec2", "question": "Who began his long TV career in 1969 as the weekend weatherman on WLWI?", "answer": "David Letterman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8836ce05a3942286d6f", "question": "A silhouette of which player is widely recognized as the inspiration behind the official NBA logo designed in 1969?", "answer": "Jerry West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0d7", "question": "Who won an Oscar for his role in the film 'The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971d", "question": "Sandra Bullock won the 2009 Best Actress Oscar for her role in which movie?", "answer": "The Blind Side", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339060", "question": "How many children did poet Sylvia Plath have?", "answer": "2", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da9", "question": "In which fictional law firm did Ally McBeal work?", "answer": "Cage, Fish and Associates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1c", "question": "Where was Ben Franklin born?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fffa2ff73838c5c8a417f1d", "question": "What is the scientific name for Earth's crust?", "answer": "Lithosphere", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59523e56736d4be723796b4e", "question": "In what decade did Toronto surpass Montreal as the most populous city in Canada?", "answer": "1970s", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3cffa4f032c0db195b495", "question": "What was the name of the military nobility of medieval and early-modern Japan?", "answer": "Samurai", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133988e", "question": "In the 1964 stop-motion TV special \"Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer\", who is Rudolph's father?", "answer": "Donner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339571", "question": "In A Charlie Brown Christmas, what does Lucy want for Christmas?", "answer": "Real Estate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab55", "question": "What is the second largest country in South America?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c76f", "question": "What rating refers to the measure of auto-ignition resistance of gasoline used in internal combustion engines?", "answer": "Octane rating", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff25a4331a458464a93c46f", "question": "What is the process called by which people set out to amass large amounts of in-game currency to sell in the real world?", "answer": "Gold farming", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bce7", "question": "What French company is represented by a mascot named \"Bibendum\"?", "answer": "Michelin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0e0", "question": "Which TV character has the surname \"Sagdiyev\"?", "answer": "Borat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff0adfee662d71a53650fb6", "question": "To raise money for charities, who handwrote an 800-word prequel to her bestselling book series?", "answer": "J.K. Rowling", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff25a9031a458464a93c473", "question": "What Dr. Seuss character was featured on the writer's license plate?", "answer": "The Grinch", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d2942596a59cbdfbd390", "question": "Who has won the most Oscars?", "answer": "Katherine Hepburn (4)", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5971ddf989261e916c8e09a0", "question": "Which character from The Simpsons tries to kill Bart Simpson on many occasions?", "answer": "Sideshow Bob", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f35", "question": "Who titled his 1989 autobiography \"Holy Cow!\"?", "answer": "Harry Caray", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff7c26d2b316f4693fb67a0", "question": "How many steps does the Empire State Building have?", "answer": "1,860", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4aa349076251badbeaba", "question": "Ancient Romans boiled vinegar and what to make an energy drink?", "answer": "Goat dung", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4c", "question": "In what year was the Sony Corporation founded?", "answer": "1946", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff6685052a821ff76ae8b03", "question": "Around what sea did Jesus call His first apostles?", "answer": "Christ first saw Peter and Andrew close to the Sea of Galilee. He beseeched them to follow Him.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e7c", "question": "Which TV show used the song \"Bad Reputation\" by Joan Jett as its theme song?", "answer": "Freaks and Geeks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5963724f967692ea851899be", "question": "A jellyfish is made up of 95% of what?", "answer": "Water", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c425", "question": "What name is usually given to bananas cultivated for cooking?", "answer": "Plantains", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339773", "question": "What is the name of the demons in Hellraiser?", "answer": "Cenobites", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d47482f8e329de4f87789d", "question": "Who was the Prime Minister of the UK throughout the 1980s?", "answer": "Marget Thatcher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b358", "question": "What was the real name of the Boston Strangler?", "answer": "Albert DeSalvo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5989a8b0cb8751d53e7d75fe", "question": "Who won Super Bowl IV?", "answer": "Kansas City Chiefs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67e", "question": "How many points must the victor score in a game of cribbage?", "answer": "61 or 121", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65857ae7e414034b5aeed", "question": "What international organization was established at the end of World War I?", "answer": "League of Nations", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c628", "question": "What is the name of the second largest planet in our Solar System?", "answer": "Saturn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391af", "question": "Who dramatically kissed Halle Berry on stage when he won Best Actor?", "answer": "Adrien Brody", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be1c", "question": "What novelist's father, Bronson, was one of the founders of the Transcendentalist movement?", "answer": "Louisa May Alcott's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d3", "question": "Which New England state does not have any ocean coastline?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a122", "question": "In the film \"The Great Escape\", what were \"Tom\", \"Dick\" and \"Harry\"?", "answer": "Three escape tunnels", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac60", "question": "Which carved stone was the key to the understanding of Egyptian hieroglyphics?", "answer": "The Rosetta Stone", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99aef21a8909e5c332d26", "question": "Who was John Lennon married to?", "answer": "Yoko Ono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973d", "question": "For which two movies did Tom Hanks win two consecutive Oscars?", "answer": "Philadelphia and Forrest Gump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a00", "question": "How many of the gifts in the song \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\" do not involve birds?", "answer": "Six", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5da855211aec824685d88d00", "question": "In what year was the \"Curse of the Bambino\" broken?", "answer": "2004", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391bb", "question": "What comedian was a drummer in the early days of the band Steely Dan?", "answer": "Chevy Chase", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aee7", "question": "Who was British Prime Minister on V-J day?", "answer": "Clement Attlee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e25", "question": "The title character of what 2000 film is a Norwich terrier name Winky?", "answer": "Best in Show", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b48d549076251badbeaa7", "question": "Who was the first African-American to travel in space?", "answer": "Guion Bluford -- On the third Challenger mission in 1983, he earned the distinction of being the first African-American in space.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339523", "question": "Who from the cast of \"The Usual Suspects\" won a Best Supporting Actor Oscar?", "answer": "Kevin Spacey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a552a23e1c6f9840ba3199", "question": "What is South Korea's telephone calling code?", "answer": "82", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea4", "question": "Which British Prime Minister had the nickname dizzy?", "answer": "Benjamin Disraelli", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a5c", "question": "According to his elementary school principal, what 1994 title character of an Oscar-winning movie had an IQ of 75?", "answer": "Forrest Gump", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa420fc73aa70ea0b70b13", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921c", "question": "What city did the band U2 form in?", "answer": "Dublin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baed", "question": "Including Jesus, how many were in attendance at The Last Supper?", "answer": "13", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea7e65ff048f679a45ac0d", "question": "Barophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b67206d333868d34d6f1", "question": "Twenty-two months of negotiation and the 1998 Good Friday Agreement ended violence in what nation?", "answer": "Northern Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a882", "question": "The former penal colony of Devil's Island is located off the coast of what country?", "answer": "French Guiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc1e", "question": "What year was the Rubik's Cube invented?", "answer": "1974", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a24", "question": "Who aimed his \"Emporio\" clothing line at younger buyers?", "answer": "Giorgio Armani", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5990f4b7fa5fdd6dd25324e4", "question": "Bengui is the capital of which land-locked country?", "answer": "Central African Republic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c803", "question": "What trade name comes from combining the French words for velvet and hook?", "answer": "Velcro", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64e", "question": "What must a mole do every four hours so it doesn't die?", "answer": "Eat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5c3e988bebfabb9c85d8a96c", "question": "Which leader was renowned for his \"Blood and Iron\" speech?", "answer": "Otto von Bismarck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60136fc1138175489539637b", "question": "What item gives the Green Lantern his power?", "answer": "Ring -- Turns out the key to being one of the most powerful superheroes in the DC universe is the ability to accessorize.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f1", "question": "What Agatha Christie novel was made up of two parts - England and Egypt?", "answer": "Death on the Nile", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40d", "question": "Devil's Island, once the world's most notorious penal colony, is located off the coast of what country?", "answer": "French Guiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c561", "question": "What is the only muscle in the human body not attached at both ends?", "answer": "Tongue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fecc34cec223966ae8f887d", "question": "Tiger Woods set or tied 27 records at which 1997 PGA tournament?", "answer": "The Masters", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5921fff1a4edfd43a087add5", "question": "Whose painting \"Irises\" was sold to Alan Bond in 1987?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd26", "question": "What Bruins and Rangers legend founded the Tampa Bay Lightning in 1991?", "answer": "Phil Esposito", "category": "general"}, {"id": "594a61ca2ebb971c1417fb8a", "question": "By what name is \"One Thousand and One Nights\" better known as in the English language?", "answer": "Arabian Nights", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a153", "question": "Who is Placebo's lead singer?", "answer": "Brian Molko", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fdf", "question": "What instrument did Lionel Hampton introduce to jazz in 1930?", "answer": "The vibraphone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66356a5bfecdd737e084f", "question": "Who was the youngest person to sign the Declaration of Independence?", "answer": "Edward Rutledge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5a4a972461d1b4d384d5d680", "question": "What is a travelator?", "answer": "Horizontal escalator, or a moving walkway", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe3e96438e4e5d4832e6310", "question": "In what years did the Mariposa War go on?", "answer": "1850 through 1851", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a89220565ad31a57c7f7", "question": "What city held the world\u2019s first major modern cat show in 1871?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b916", "question": "What 2 letters in scrabble have the highest point value?", "answer": "Q and Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5c4", "question": "Which word in computing is used to describe half of a byte?", "answer": "Nibble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfd", "question": "The eyewear brand Ray Ban was founded what year?", "answer": "1937", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938d", "question": "Where did Rocky Balboa keep his gym locker combination?", "answer": "In his hat", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7350aeec85e375820b242", "question": "What was the name of President Lyndon B. Johnson's wife?", "answer": "Claudia Alta \"Lady Bird\" Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60173cac44491cbd7c5a17a7", "question": "How did Saturday get its name?", "answer": "Saturday is named for Saturn. The word is derived from S\u00e6turnesd\u00e6g\u00a0in Old English,\u00a0dies Saturni\u00a0in Latin and samedi\u00a0in French.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b23", "question": "What book was Mark David Chapman carrying when he shot John Lennon?", "answer": "The Catcher in the Rye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe529341bf59ab7d2e38100", "question": "What would you get if you were to receive a Xoloitzcuintli as a gift?", "answer": "A dog", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b30b", "question": "Who uttered the line \"There you go again\" during a debate?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54b", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Alabama?", "answer": "Montgomery", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91e", "question": "What does breaking the sound barrier cause?", "answer": "A Sonic Boom", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba46b874c93a3298b2144", "question": "What does the word \"economy\" mean in Ancient Greek?", "answer": "Household management", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69b7220565ad31a57c75f", "question": "What English code breaker created a machine that helped to decrypt Nazi messages?", "answer": "Alan Turing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3c3", "question": "What is the name for a baby turkey?", "answer": "Poult", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b510", "question": "What do you get when you add fresh fruit to red wine?", "answer": "Sangria", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3d", "question": "Professional tennis player, Rafael Nadal, is of what nationality?", "answer": "Spanish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f4a", "question": "What Latin phrase actually comes from a poem, attributed to Virgil, about a salad recipe?", "answer": "E Pluribus Unum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b38e", "question": "Which crew sank in the 1978 Boat Race?\u00a0", "answer": "Cambridge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa438ec73aa70ea0b70b16", "question": "Where is the observatory where Percival Lowell first theorized the existence of Pluto?", "answer": "Flagstaff, Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7db", "question": "In which US state is the headquarters for the Mayo Clinic?", "answer": "Minnesota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3e4", "question": "What is Chicago's main international airport?", "answer": "O'Hare", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16a8af7c52aae91cc07de", "question": "In Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\", what are the names of the three spirits?", "answer": "Iris, Ceres and Juno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5cc", "question": "What is the name given to the largest number ever used in a mathematical proof?", "answer": "Graham's Number", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a307", "question": "Who played the role of David Duchovny's daughter on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Madeleine Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbfe", "question": "What year were the Ray-Ban Wayfarer sunglasses introduced to the market?", "answer": "1956", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f1686af7c52aae91cc07c6", "question": "What is the common name for solid carbon dioxide?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9f6", "question": "What is a peanut if it is not a pea or a nut?", "answer": "Legume", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd9757e83c707845b217a", "question": "How old was Sheldon Cooper when he earned his PhD?", "answer": "He went on to earn himself a PhD at the young age of 16.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601737b944491cbd7c5a178d", "question": "What military leader is believed to have said, \"I can run wild for six months\u00a0... after that, I have no expectation of success\".", "answer": "Japanese Admiral\u00a0Isoroku Yamamoto -- He said this while predicting the future outcome of naval war against the U.S.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38b", "question": "What is the name for a human third molar?", "answer": "A wisdom tooth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d47006f8e329de4f87788c", "question": "Who is credited with inventing the saxophone?", "answer": "Adolphe Sax", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b6649076251badbeac4", "question": "Maya Angelou spoke at the inauguration of which U.S. President?", "answer": "Maya Angelou recited her poem \"On the Pulse of Morning,\" at President Bill Clinton's first inauguration in 1993.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc40", "question": "What nationality is tennis player Roger Federer?", "answer": "Swiss", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c549", "question": "What planet was named after the goddess of beauty?", "answer": "Venus", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea3deaff048f679a45ab56", "question": "What is the only moon in the solar system that has an atmosphere?", "answer": "Titan", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ac", "question": "What is Homer Simpson's middle initial?", "answer": "J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cddcae347d002c297e4f4", "question": "Who played the lead in the movie \"The Mask\"?", "answer": "Jim Carrey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339629", "question": "In what movie does Bruce Willis play a ghost?", "answer": "The Sixth Sense", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefc4206ce05a3942286f2d", "question": "What is the name of the ramrod in the television series \"Rawhide\"?", "answer": "Rowdy Yates", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601370831381754895396382", "question": "In the 1990 film \"Home Alone\", the fictitious film that Kevin watches, \"Angels with Filthy Souls\", is a homage to what real film?", "answer": "\"Angels with Dirty Faces\" -- It is a 1938 gangster film starring James Cagney and Pat O'Brien.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d85", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"Nosferatu\" based on?", "answer": "Dracula", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "592205cea4edfd43a087adea", "question": "Of which country did F.W. de Klerk become president in 1989?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b184", "question": "What year was US President Ronald Reagan born?", "answer": "1911", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4b9949076251badbeac5", "question": "The Iditarod Trail Sled Dog Race was inspired in part by what event?", "answer": "A diphtheria outbreak -- In 1925, several teams of mush dogs relayed a serum for diphtheria from Seward to Nome, Alaska.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59523f68736d4be723796b58", "question": "What year were the Canada's Juno Awards first awarded?", "answer": "1970", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac0f", "question": "Moroni is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Comoros", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f5d", "question": "In the series Harry Potter, what is the spell for water-making?", "answer": "Aguamenti", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b619", "question": "Who was the first female to be featured on the front of a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Mary Lou Retton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b7f", "question": "Who wrote \"Allegory of the Cave\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338979", "question": "What card game is featured in the novel \"Casino Royale\"?", "answer": "Baccarat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59049cfccf93664eb10486ab", "question": "What is the more common name for the 1987 computer virus that was set to go off on Friday the 13th of every year?", "answer": "Jerusalem", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adcd", "question": "Which German Military leader of World War I became President of Germany in 1925?", "answer": "Paul von Hindenburg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd21", "question": "What company originally owned the name \"Saltine\" before losing it to trademark dilution?", "answer": "Nabisco", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe522ae1bf59ab7d2e380e9", "question": "\"100% Squeezed Sunshine\" has been which company's ad slogan?", "answer": "Tropicana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a90620565ad31a57c7fb", "question": "Who shot Lee Harvey Oswald?", "answer": "Jack Ruby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fef5f286ce05a3942286e3e", "question": "What villainous role did comedian Jim Carrey play in \"Batman Forever\"?", "answer": "The Riddler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b664", "question": "In a deck of Bicycle brand playing cards, what type of character is depicted riding a bicycle on the Joker card?", "answer": "A king", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1f", "question": "A nilometer measures the level of what?", "answer": "The river Nile", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2cfc92596a59cbdfbd373", "question": "Who said, \"My Best Friend is a person who will give me a book I have not read\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec8aa4ec223966ae8f8833", "question": "Who ended his final 60 Minutes segment by saying \"if you do see me in a restaurant, please, just let me eat my dinner\"?", "answer": "Andy Rooney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5902a0c8cad1ec93f27df770", "question": "How much larger is UK pint compared to the US pint?", "answer": "About 20%, or 95 mL", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a138", "question": "Who sang the theme song to the film \"The Breakfast Club\"?", "answer": "Simple Minds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4d9abc08b8581f80b092bf", "question": "What big budget game was the subject of monetization controversy and government interference in the fall of 2017?", "answer": "Star Wars Battlefront II", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9c2", "question": "What is Albumen the correct term for?", "answer": "Egg White", "category": "science"}, {"id": "601b4c8749076251badbead6", "question": "What was the first country to put a woman in space?", "answer": "The Soviet Union -- In 1963, cosmonaut Valentina Tereshkova\u00a0orbited the Earth 48 times in a space capsule named Vostok 6.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c35e89a6b7193fa56721f83", "question": "How many strings are on a baritone ukulele?", "answer": "4", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59636b6d967692ea851899a5", "question": "Which country, that ceased to be a US territory in 1946, celebrates July 4 as its \"Republic Day\"?", "answer": "The Philippines", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fec88caec223966ae8f8823", "question": "Which pop media icon was recently memorialized in \"World of Warcraft\" in late 2018?", "answer": "Stan Lee", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58c8a62390aac110e416707b", "question": "What popular tea is named after an 1830\u2019s United Kingdom Prime Minister?", "answer": "Earl Grey tea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999e", "question": "How many episodes of \"Petticoat Junction\" were made?", "answer": "222", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4e0e006d333868d34d722", "question": "\"An eye for an eye and a tooth for a tooth\" is a well-known phrase from what collection of 282 laws?", "answer": "The Code of Hammurabi", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339da3", "question": "Who played the role of the US president in the movie \"Canadian Bacon\"?", "answer": "Alan Alda", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bbd4c7400d154d7af00b8d1", "question": "What year did Snoop Dogg release his debut album?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa1", "question": "Rex Stout created what private eye?", "answer": "Nero Wolfe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a5", "question": "What is the Japanese name for Japan?", "answer": "Nippon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad79", "question": "What ships did Vikings sail in?", "answer": "Longboats", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133897d", "question": "What was Long John Silver's parrot Captain Flint favorite phrase?", "answer": "Pieces of eight", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339906", "question": "What elderly TV detective came out of retirement after his son, Hal, was killed?", "answer": "Barnaby Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93b", "question": "What month features the harvest moon?", "answer": "September", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ebf", "question": "Whose girlfriends are named Callie Shaw and Iola Morton?", "answer": "The Hardy Boys", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917b", "question": "Whose author's novel is the movie \"The Godfather\" based on?", "answer": "Mario Puzo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338efc", "question": "Which literary work's title character is named Frankie Addams?", "answer": "The Member of the Wedding", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb59d35dad637d903c8815", "question": "What is the largest county in the United States?", "answer": "San Bernardino County, California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e7e", "question": "During what war was the novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\" set?", "answer": "Seven Years' War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b522", "question": "What popular operating system are the Mac OS X series based on?", "answer": "Unix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a695", "question": "What is the official language of Guyana?", "answer": "English", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597cd5fde347d002c297e4b9", "question": "Which major horserace is held in Australia on the first Tuesday in November?", "answer": "The Melbourne Cup", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae4", "question": "What 2001 Rachael Leigh Cook film was based on an old Saturday morning cartoon series?", "answer": "Josie and the Pussycats", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b489", "question": "For how many years was the first generation Volkswagen Golf in production?", "answer": "9 years", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b646", "question": "On the standard Monopoly board, what color are the Chance cards?", "answer": "Orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59c1cd8c7bd84c0ea43ad429", "question": "Skopje is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Macedonia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a092", "question": "Who sang \"That's Alright Mama\"?", "answer": "Elvis Presley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5fb", "question": "Which is the biggest planet in our Solar System?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ff", "question": "What is the official name of New York's Sixth Avenue?", "answer": "Avenue of the Americas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597ddf6d77980686f722d185", "question": "What city was host to the first official Association football game in 1863?", "answer": "London", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefbfda6ce05a3942286f06", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Tango in the Night\"?", "answer": "Fleetwood Mac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e6bd30fb6c85e9e634ff64", "question": "Who won the World Series in 1987?", "answer": "Minnesota Twins", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe734c9eec85e375820b23c", "question": "Who chaired the \"Wannsee Conference\" during World War II?", "answer": "Reinhard Heydrich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c131877e98cb97778975", "question": "Where is Grant\u2019s Tomb?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afba", "question": "Who was the last Viceroy to India?", "answer": "Lord Mountbatten", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a35e", "question": "Where is the International Court of Justice?", "answer": "The Hague", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60062a58c9d816e292245c17", "question": "What is Judy Chicago's most well-known work?", "answer": "Regarded as the first epic feminist artwork, \"The Dinner Party\" functions as a symbolic history of women in Western civilization.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ce", "question": "In what country were Trabant cars made?", "answer": "East Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e17", "question": "What French Wave director plays the UFO expert in \"Close Encounters of the Third Kind\"?", "answer": "Francois Truffaut", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5febd5bb7e83c707845b2165", "question": "Which inventor developed the solid-body electric guitar that made rock 'n roll possible?", "answer": "Les Paul", "category": "entertainment"}]